We will often see people talking about benefits
我們會經常看到人們談論收益
But few people talk about the cost
但是卻很少有人談論代價
For example
就比如說
Some ETFs have been very popular in recent years
最近幾年有一些ETF非常的火
They use the option strategy of Covered Call
他們使用Covered Call這種期權策略
To achieve high dividends
來實現高分紅
Their dividend rate
他們的分紅率
Usually more than 10%
通常是達到10%以上
Some even exceed 100%
甚至有的超過100%
It looks very attractive
看起來非常的有吸引力
But have you ever thought about it?
但是你有沒有思考過
Such a high dividend rate
這麼高的分紅率
What is the price behind it
它背後的代價是什麼
Good today's video
好今天的影片
Let's discuss
我們就來討論
On the topic of high dividend costs
關於高分紅代價這個話題
I will also share one
同時我也會分享一種
Very simple way
非常簡單的方法
To avoid these pitfalls
來避免這些坑
Help you find
幫助你找到
Targets worth investing in for the long term
值得長期投資的標的
Let's take a look at an ETF first
我們先來看一隻ETF
TSLY
TSLY
This is a company that uses Tesla stock as the target
這是一隻以特斯拉股票為標的
Covered Call Options Strategy ETF
的Covered Call期權策略ETF
It pays out as much as 120%
它的分紅率高達120%
Very tempting
非常的誘人
Look at it from the top of its historical return curve
從它的歷史回報曲線上面來看
Since the listing of this ETF
從這隻ETF上市以來
It has been obtained
它一共獲得了
23% composite rate of return
23%的綜合回報率
It looks pretty good
看上去還不錯
Still positive returns
還是正收益
But if you remove its dividends
但是如果你去掉它的分紅
Look at its net worth curve
看它的淨值曲線
The net worth is from 41 Dollar
淨值從41塊
Now it has dropped to less than 8 Dollar
現在是下降到了不到8塊錢
Less than three years
三年不到的時間
It has depreciated by 80%
已經貶值了80%
Then this is called
那麼這就是叫做
Typical high dividend traps
典型的高分紅陷阱
In a layman's term
用一句通俗一點的話來說
You get its dividends
你獲得它的分紅
It takes your principal
它拿走你的本金
Let's take another look
那麼再來看一個
NVDY
NVDY
This is a stock that is based on Nvidia stock
這是一隻以英偉達股票為標的
Covered Call Options Strategy ETF
Covered Call期權策略ETF
Then its dividend rate is as high as 70% or more
那麼它的分紅率高達70%以上
When it is at its highest
最高的時候
Even more than 120%
甚至超過120%
This ETF
這隻ETF
Consolidated return since listing
從上市以來的綜合回報率
Up to 270%
高達270%
But its net asset value
但是它的資產淨值
But it dropped by 10%
卻下降了10%
Why is this happening?
為什麼會這樣呢
Let's find out
我們來了解一下
Fundamentals of Covered Call Options Strategy
Covered Call期權策略的基本原理
To make it easy to read
為了讀起來順口
Then I will abbreviate it as below
那麼下面我就把它簡稱為
It's called a CC strategy
叫做CC策略
CC strategy is simply a matter of fact
CC策略簡單來說
You buy a bunch of stocks first
就是你先買一堆股票
Then sell the call option on the stock
然後賣出股票的看漲期權
It is equivalent to your right to sell a stock to rise
相當於你賣出了股票上漲的權利
This way you can collect royalties
這樣你可以收取權利金
Royalties are CC policy
權利金是CC策略
The main source of income
最主要的收益來源
But this strategy
但是這個策略
There are some obvious flaws
有一些明顯的缺陷
First
首先
The Nature of CC Strategy
CC策略的本質
is bearish
是看跌的
Because it's a sell-bullish sell
因為是賣出看漲嘛
Sell the right to rise to others
把上漲的權利賣給了別人
Then if at the stipulated time
那麼如果在規定的時間
The share price rises to the price specified in the contract
股價漲到了合約規定的價格
Then the fund must sell the shares
那麼基金就必須要賣出股票
If the condition is not met
如果說不滿足條件
Then the fund can keep shares
那麼基金可以保留股票
But anyway
但無論如何
This strategy can also make a lot of money
這個策略都可以穩賺權利金
But there is a problem here
但是這裡有一個問題
That is to say
就是說
The rising stock market environment
持續上漲的股市環境
It is very detrimental to the CC strategy
對CC策略是非常不利的
Then the stock price continues to rise
那麼股價不斷的上漲
Then the CC strategy has to continue to sell stocks
那麼CC策略就不得不持續的賣出股票
Thus making the whole net worth
從而就使得整個的淨資產
In a gradual reduction
在逐步的減少
But the market continues to fall
但是持續下跌的市場
For CC Strategy
對CC策略來說
It's even worse
就更不利了
If you say
如果說
Stock prices continue to plummet
股價持續的大跌
Then the premium received by the fund
那麼基金收到的權利金
Insufficient to cover assets
不足以彌補資產
The degree of continuous shrinkage
持續縮水的這個程度
Then at the same time
那麼同時
High dividends are also paid to investors
還要支付給投資者高額的分紅
Then there is no doubt
那麼毫無疑問
Net worth will decline faster and faster
淨資產下降的速度會越來越快
So we mentioned earlier
所以我們前面提到
TSLY's net worth has shrunk relatively largely
TSLY它的淨值縮水比較大
Mainly because of Tesla's stock price in the past two years
主要就是因為特斯拉這兩年的股價
Basically not much increase
基本沒怎麼漲
Then continue to pay high dividends
那麼持續高分紅
Consuming a significant amount of net worth
消耗了大量的淨資產
Compared with
相比之下
NVDY's net worth has shrunk relatively little
NVDY的淨值縮水程度比較小
Then it's because of Nvidia stock
那麼也就是因為英偉達股票
The rise has continued in the past two years
這兩年持續的上漲
But even so
但是即便是如此
The principal amount of investment is still shrinking
投資本金依然在縮水
The market environment that CC strategy is most suitable for
CC策略最適合的市場環境
It doesn't go up or down
就是不大漲也不大跌
This is a market that moves upwards with slight fluctuations
這種小幅震盪往上走的行情
Therefore, the CC strategy is the most suitable target
所以CC策略最適合的標的
It's not a stock
其實不是股票
It is the broader market index of US stocks
而是美股的大盤指數
Take the S&amp;P 500 index, for example
比如說標普500指數
Or the Nasdaq 100
或者納斯達克100指數
These two indices
這兩個指數
Most of the time
在大多數這個時候
It's that gentle
它就是這種溫和的
Slightly up
小幅上漲
This upward trend of vibration
震動的這種向上走的行情
In summary, the characteristics of the CC strategy are:
總之CC策略的特點是
Limited gains
上漲有限
But the decline is infinite
但是下跌無限
If you find one
如果說你發現一隻
Net ETF Value of CC Strategy
CC策略的ETF淨值
It is constantly shrinking
是在持續縮水的
So I think you've seen this video
那麼我想你看過這個影片之後
You should know how
你應該知道怎麼做了
So I usually observe the changes in the net value of ETFs
那麼我平時觀察ETF淨值變化
I recommend using Koyfin.com
我是推薦使用Koyfin.com
This website
這個網站
Free is enough
免費的就夠用了
Then go to this website
那麼進入這個網站
Then enter the subject code
然後輸入標的代碼
Select the historical price chart
選擇歷史價格圖表
Then add another piece of data
然後再添加一條數據
Input NAV
輸入NAV
You can see it
就可以看到
The change data of net asset value
資產淨值的變化數據了
I need to make a statement here
這裡我需要聲明一下
Between me and Koyfin
我與Koyfin之間
There is no money exchange
沒有任何金錢往來
I just think it's easy to use and recommend it to everyone
我只是覺得好用推薦給大家
It is not to advertise him in any way
並不是給他做任何廣告
Then I believe
那麼我相信
There are also other tools
也有其他的某一些工具
Maybe I don't know
也許我不知道
A similar effect can be achieved
也可以實現類似的效果
In addition
除此之外
There is an easier way
還有一種更簡單的方式
For example
比如說
We use TradingView
我們使用tradingview
Enter the code
輸入代碼
Get the trend chart
得到走勢圖
Then in the lower right corner
然後在右下角
Turn off the button for adjusting dividends
把根據分紅調整的按鈕關掉
This is how it can be seen
這樣就可以看到
Price movement excluding dividends
不包含分紅的價格走勢
If you use it
如果說你使用
Software like Futubull
富途牛牛之類的軟件
Then change the option of removal to non-reinstatement
那麼把除權的選項變為不復權
The same effect can be achieved
也可以實現同樣的效果
We need to find it
我們需要找到
This dividend rate is relatively high
這種分紅率相對比較高
However, the net asset value
但是資產淨值
It should not be a subject that has shrunk significantly
它不要大幅縮水的標的
Then the best target
那麼最好的標的
Of course
當然就是說
The dividend rate is relatively high
分紅率比較高
Concurrent net asset value
同時資產淨值
You can go up
可以往上走的
Those who can gradually improve
能夠逐漸提高的
Then this is what we deserve
那麼這就是我們值得
Long-term investment target
長期投資的標的
I mentioned it earlier
前面我提到過
That is to say, the most suitable target for the CC strategy
就是說cc策略最適合的標的
It is a broader market index of US stocks
是美股的大盤指數
In this chart
這張圖表當中
I have listed a few
我列舉了一些
It is currently more popular in the market
目前市場上比較熱門的
The S&amp;P 500 index
以標普500指數
Or the Nasdaq 100
或者納斯達克100指數
CC policy for the target
為標的的cc策略
ETFs with high dividends
高分紅的ETF
Compare it this way
這樣對比來看
From March 2024 to the present
從2024年3月到現在
Top 3 with the highest combined returns
綜合回報最高的前三名
It's QDTE
是QDTE
QQQI and SPYI
那QQQI和SPYI
Then after removing the dividends
那麼去掉分紅之後
The top three with a relatively good net worth level
淨資產水平保持比較好的前三名
It's DIVO
是DIVO
QQQI和JEPQ
QQQI和JEPQ
If the end time is set to April 8, 2025
如果把結束的時間設定在2025年4月8日
We can see
我們可以看到
In the course of a market decline
在市場下跌的過程當中
Changes in the net assets of these ETFs
這些ETF淨資產的變化情況
Then we can also observe
那麼我們也可以觀察
In the process of gradual market recovery
在隨後市場逐漸恢復的過程當中
Their net worth performance
他們的淨值表現
I don't want to say which one is better here
在這裡我不想說哪個好
Which is bad
哪個不好
I believe you have understood these principles
我相信你搞懂了這些原理之後
You will judge yourself
你自己是會有判斷
So today's video
那麼今天這支影片
My main purpose
我主要的目的
I still want to share such an approach
還是想分享這樣的一種方法
Instead of giving conclusions
而不是給出結論
Then there are netizens who have been asking me
那麼一直也有網友在問我
Why is my Hi5 in the mix?
為什麼我的 Hi5 組合當中
No CC policy is configured
不配置cc策略
This ETF is used to obtain cash flow
這種ETF來獲取現金流
Then this question
那麼這個問題
I have two main concerns
我主要是有兩個顧慮
The first is the CC strategy
第一個就是cc策略
Overall
總體上來說
They both have relatively short histories
他們都歷史還比較短
I have never experienced anything of the same magnitude as it was in 2008
沒有經歷過像2008年這種量級的
The test of the financial crisis
金融危機的考驗
The second is the CC strategy
第二個就是說cc策略
It is basically an active management strategy
基本上都是一個主動管理型策略
Then proactive management
那麼主動管理
It means that there is an element of human beings
意味著就有人的因素在其中
So I think
那麼我認為
Everything that someone does
凡是有人做的事情
Mistakes are bound to occur
就一定會出錯
There will be mistakes in some human weaknesses
會出一些人性的弱點之錯
Then I like it
那麼我喜歡
Subject matter in which no one intervenes
沒有人干預的標的
In addition, it is said
另外就是說
ETFs have a herd effect
ETF都是有羊群效應的
When the market is good
行情好的時候
Continuous inflow of funds
資金不斷的流入
Then for this
那麼對於這種
For ETFs with high dividends
高分紅的ETF來說
He can use the new money
他可以用新來的資金
To provide dividends to old customers
來為老的客戶提供分紅
But when the market is bad
但是行情不好的時候
Funds continue to flow out
資金持續流出
In this case
那麼這種狀況下
This kind of game chain
這種遊戲鏈條
It may break
有可能就會斷裂
Then in extreme cases
那麼極端情況下
It may result in the winding-up of the fund
有可能會導致基金被清盤
This means
那麼這就意味著
Investors may lose all their money
投資者有可能血本無歸
Anyway, my current policy on CC
總之我目前對cc策略
Still keep a called
還是保持一種叫做
Optimistic and cautious attitude
樂觀謹慎的態度
Always be vigilant
時刻警惕著
There is a possibility that he will take my principal
他有可能會拿走我的本金
So I think about today's video
那麼我想今天這個影片
Such a simple way
這樣一個簡單的方法
It should be said that you understand
應該說你理解之後
Be able to use this method well
能夠用好這個方法
You can avoid most pitfalls
你可以避掉絕大多數坑
Then for this
那麼對於這種
These things about high dividends
高分紅的這些事情
Don't be profitable
不要被收益
Attract attention
吸引了眼球
And forgot
而忘記了
We invest in hope
我們投資最終還是希望
There is a continuous growth of assets
有一個資產的持續的增長
Good
好
Then let's talk about that
那麼就說這些
Today's video
今天這個影片
I hope to be able to give it to everyone
我希望能夠給大家
Offer a new way of thinking
提供一個新的思路
I'm Lao Lei
我是老雷
See you in the next video
我們下個影片再見
Bye
拜拜